ANA MARIA CIFUENTES

Phone number +57 319 530 9020 Whatsapp +14704395362

Email anacifuentesco@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/anacifuentesco/



2010

SUMMARY

Bilingual Industrial Engineer with international experience. Looking forward to be part of a company that drives engineering innovation and digital transformation. I specialized in the administration of continuous improvement projects working closely with the Product Owner and the technical team by seeking and delivering solutions as a result of implementing technological systems and applying re-engineering. Highly efficient and responsible with great communication and leadership skills. With five years of work experience participating in large projects developing my knowledge in analyzing business requirements, driving UATs and getting experience in systems administration as SAP HCM, SuccessFactors, SharePoint and Saas.

EXPERIENCE

Open Intl Cali, Colombia **Product Specialist** 2018 - Present

UCB Pharma Brussels, Belgium HR Knowledge & Technology Analyst 2016 - 2017

- SuccessFactors Project:
 - Part of the core team as leader of the global access management and legal track, defining the roles based permissions
 - Responsible of the implementation of the legal requirements of 5 European countries by means of workshops and UATs with the local champions, consultants and the technical team
 - Participating in UATs for the global requirements and delivering test scenarios as part of the access roles designing
 - Supporting local and global workshops to define processes, legal requirements and set of data to be available in SuccessFactors
- Defining the evaluation model for the developing competencies of the employees to be implemented in SuccessFactors
- Running the access audit per quarter for both systems SAP HR and SuccessFactors
- Supporting the annual compensation review by ensuring the correct access of Business Partners globally and updating SuccessFactors through an interface with SAP HCM to ensure the payment of bonus, merit and LTIs
- Neocase (Shared Services) project: Coordinating the translation of the system in 9 languages and leading the testing track to ensure the right translation and functionality of the portal

Georgia, United States **UCB Pharma** 2015 - 2016

HR Project Management Analyst

- Project lead for launching the Shared Services for Brazil:
 - Creating and managing the product development roadmap to successfully meet all assigned timelines; enabling the company to serve the entire Americas region by target date
 - Effectively managed cross-cultural communication between Brazil, U.S. and Belgium (HQ) offices to meet local requirements for shared services materials
 - Worked diligently with IT and external agencies to overcome technical challenges with HR Connector, Lync and associated equipment to complete UAT
- Supporting the Human Resources Business Partner with data analysis to identify the turnover rate in the USA (MS Excel), resulting in measurable improvements and winning showcases for the new Human Talent improvements globally
- Advising the internal client with topics related to Human Resources
- Supporting internal audit to ensure the quality of employee records
- Delivering the recruitment survey and quick reference guide to improve the onboarding process

Cultural Care Colorado, United States 2012 - 2014Au Pair

Banco de Occidente Cali, Colombia **Process and Project Analyst** (2010-2012) (2014-2015)

Leader in improvement projects for the departments of Electronic Channels, Front and Back Office, Foreign Trade, International Business, Customer Service and Human Talent.

EDUCATION

Industrial Engineering Degree, Professional Degree -Colombia Universidad San Buenaventura de Cali 2006-2012 Operations Management: Developing Competitive Advantages under Lean Manufacturing, Certificate -Colombia

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native), English (Fluent), French (Basic)

Centro Colombiano de Estudios Profesionales